HARSH KUMAR GOEL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | COMPETITIVE CODER

+91 8077171949 | harshkumargoel.3468@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Node.is
- React.js
- Firebase
- · CSS, HTML, JavaScript
- Core Java
- MongoDB
- REST API
- SQL
- Python
- GitHub
- AWS Fundamentals
- Data Structures and Algorithms

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Creative Spirit
- Reliable and Professional
- Organized
- Time Management
- Team Player
- Fast Learner
- Motivated

LINKS

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/h arsh-kumar-goel-366109152/
- https://github.com/harsh3468

CERTIFICATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Core Java certificate from ABES Engineering College.
- Python Basics certificate from Amity Future Academy.
- 26th rank in National Shooting Championship.
- Geeks Of The Galaxy Hackathon Certificate (Inter College).
- 1st rank in Pre U.P State Shooting Championship (Gold Medalist).
- Ranked under 3000 in HackWithInfy contest.
- AWS Fundamentals certificate from Coursera.
- Ranked under top 5 teams in Smart India Hackathon (Intra College).

POSITION OF RESPONSIBILTY

- Promotions team member in Abhivyakti (College Club).
- Lead in tech club(Tech Explorator).

PROJECTS

• SERVICE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

A scalable service management panel with ease of use and many flexible operations. The Team consisted of 3 members and the project was developed as per the problem requirement.

<u>Responsibility</u>: My responsibilities included working as a Backend Developer and Application Developer.

<u>Technologies</u>: Handlebars, Node.JS, HTML, CSS, REST API, MongoDB.

• PRODUCTS MANAGEMENT PANEL

This project involved building up a Products Management Panel which catered to admin. Involved in developing a Web-based Application which would enable admin to handle different operations on products and get orders details whenever new order created.

<u>Responsibility</u>: I worked on designing of database using Firebase, Frontend Development, API creation and Integration.

Technologies: Firebase, React.JS, Node.JS, Material UI.

NETWORKING PLATFORM

An application developed for Social Networking. Where users can perform multiple operations such as post, comment, like, etc. Users get different notifications as well as recommendations based on their field of interest.

<u>Responsibility</u>: I was involved in Database and Application Development.

Technologies: Firebase, React.JS, Node.JS, Material UI.

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Go Perceptive | Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

- Studied basic project requirements and planned development strategies.
- Researched new technologies and software packages for use in projects.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines,

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Hyathi Technology | Feb 2021 - April 2021

- Supported web applications and websites through database development.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3 and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device, and operating system compatibility.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING ABES Engineering College | 2017 - 2021 | CGPA:

CLASS XII (CBSE)

Silver Bells Public School | 2016 - 2017 | Percentage: 91%

HOBBIES

• Singing, Swimming, Shooting, Painting, Coding.